it turns out that Russia came to defend the
получается что Россия пришла защищать э
Donbass and did so
Донбасс так и сделала разрушений и
more destruction than you can even
больше чем вот вообще можно даже
imagine in that
представить на том
Donbass, what is the logic of
Донбассе в чём тогда логика
defense then? Hello good afternoon Yes, I’m
защиты Здравствуй добрый день Да я у
asking people from Russia how you
людей из России спрашиваю как вы
feel about the war in Ukraine, we are immediately
относитесь к войне в Украине мы сразу
against the war  in Ukraine he’s super I’m
вот мы против войны в Украине супер он Я
against it Well, let’s talk to the one who’s talking now,
против А ну давай с тем кто за сейчас
he likes to talk I don’t want to argue with
он любит общаться Я не хочу спорить с
you Well, why Switch by why do
вами Ну почему Переключай по зачем зачем
we need emotions, look at people like We need to
нам сес эмоции смотри людей типа Надо
somehow stop this war,
как-то останавливать эту войну
figure out who’s right and who’s
разобраться кто прав кто не
wrong can  we are wrong, maybe we need to
прав может мы не правы может нам надо
give up
сдаться
Svani
свани
for went back to
для ушёл назад в
Russia Work brothers Work so that there
Россию Работайте братья Работайте чтобы
is more This is what you mean in order to
было больше Вот это имеешь виду чтоб
work
работаеть
Yeah I don’t want to talk to you now something
Ага я не хочу сейчас с вами что-то тут
like emotionally communicate I have no
как эмоционально общаться У меня нет
desire We are not emotional I won’t
желани мы не эмоционально я не буду
swear  I’m communicating with people purely logically.
ругаться я вот чисто логически общаюсь с
Well, let’s talk logically.
людьми Ну давайте логически пообщаемся
Let’s see. What are your motives for supporting this war? Look, I support him from the point of view so that nothing threatens Russia. And how does Ukraine threaten Russia? Ukraine wanted to join NATO and what do you see?  if Ukraine
и что смотрите если бы Украина вступила
would join NATO and the Americans would America,
бы в НАТО а американские бы Америка по
there are some naked men walking around behind them,
там какие-то голые мужики сзади ходят
they are just making a bet, I understand everything,
они просто занимаются на спор всё понял
post there beds, two naked men, this is
пост тамм кровати два голых мужика это
Russia, Ponya SBO Well, NATO Yeah, and if
Россия Поня СБО Ну НАТО Угу Вот и если
they joined NATO, then  with a high
они вступили бы в НАТО бы то с большой
probability there would be
вероятностью бы там бы стояли бы
American military bases there and
американские военные базы И нам бы
America would manipulate us.
Америка нами бы манипулировать бы Верно
True, true. Because of this, I suppose
верно Вот из-за этого я предполагаю
the war started, but look,
началась война а вот смотрите э вот вы в
what city do you live in? Well, in what region of
каком городе живёте Ну в каком регионе
Russia in St. Petersburg O
России в санкт-петербург О
St. Petersburg is cool, here you are next to
санкт-петербург круто вот у вас рядом
Estonia Latvia Lithuania they are in NATO yes Yeah
Эстония Латвия Литва они в НАТО да Угу
for about 20 years
уже лет 20
I guess so why don’t you attack
Наверно так почему вот вы не надае на
them, that is, they are already in NATO and there is no
них то есть они уже в НАТО и никакой
threat to you from the
угрозы вам нет от
funniest thing that Vladimir
ни самое смешное что Владимир
Vladimirovich is
Владимирович л на них
attacking them  and
напра и ещё
also We, so to speak, the Russian
ещё Мы же так сказать Российская
Federation liberated the DPR LPR from Well, from the
Федерация же освободила ДНР лнр от Ну от
Nazis Wait, let’s howl like that
нацистов Подождите давайте так выли
because NATO didn’t come here or you
из-за того что НАТО тут не зашло или вы
liberated something, let’s
что-то освобождали давайте
differentiate
разграничить
Yeah So good, that is, it turns out And in
Ага Так хорошо то есть получается А в
Estonia, Latvia is there
Эстонии Латвии там есть
nationalists, I can’t know this, I
националисты я знать не могу этого я
just talked honestly with a man
просто сам общался честно с человеком
who is from Ukraine, just like you and
который с Украины вот так вот как мы с
me, and he told me that he doesn’t
вами и он говорил мне то что он не
like dark-skinned guys, I asked
любит темнокожих парней есть спросил у
him if there are such people in Ukraine. No, he
него есть ли в Украине такие Нет он
says that
говорит то что
only  there is Well, he’s like he’s
э только есть Ну вот и он типа там их
walking around beating them there stop wait That is, you
ходит бьёт там стоп подожди То есть ты
want to say that in Russia in St. Petersburg and in
хочешь сказать что в России в Питере и в
Moscow there are no skins who beat
Москве нет каких-то скинов которые бьют
and everyone is called face see face I’m
и всех называют лицо видите лицо Я
saying that there are such faces see he’s
говорю что есть такие лиц видите он гово
in Moscow  and in St. Petersburg there are so many of these
в Москве и в Питере там столько этих
skinheads and it was a long time ago and Russian marches
скинхедов и было давно и русские марши
went to zigging that there was no such thing,
ходили зиговать что не было такого
parry parry, but it seems to me Well, yes, I
парируй парируй но мне кажется Ну да
agree in Moscow, St. Petersburg there are 100%, but it
согласен в Москве Питере есть 100% но
seems to me that in Ukraine it somehow
мне кажется в Украине это как-то
flourishes differently because you
по-другому процветает потому что у вас
but there are no, as far as I know, as far as I
же там нет как мне известно как мне
know, I don’t know, you don’t have
известно я не знаю там нет у вас там
Uzbeks, Tajiks there, and the like. There are
узбеков таджиков там и тому подобное Вот
such
таких
cash registers. Well, why won’t Putin
касов Ну так Почему Россия Путин не
overcome Russia? This is Nazism in St. Petersburg and in
поборет Вот это нацизм в Питере и в
Moscow, where in reality there are
Москве где реально
some attacks on Tajiks and Caucasians
таджиков кавказцев каких-то напада на
they are good and the
них хорошо а
Tajiks Maybe there is Nazism in Russia,
таджики Может с есть в России нацизм
so why is Russia not
есть есть так то Почему Россия не
fighting it in Russia, but fighting somewhere
борется с ним в России а борется где-то
in Ukraine with some mystical
в Украине с какими-то мистичны
nationalists
националистами
Well, after all, for
Ну сри натяжения
many years, there, near the DPR and
сколько-то лет Там же около ДНР
LPR, the
лнр
Nazis were a nightmare there  Well, well, DPR
там нацисты кошмарили же ну ДНР
ln Well, there are people like that, well,
лн Ну там и тому подобное людей как ну
again, I know how many
как мне опять же известно сколько они
people they are and how in what
людей и как в какой
ways. I don’t know how many, where did you get
способы Я не знаю сколько откуда у вас
this information from, that some Nazis
такая информация что какие-то нацисты
somehow took and killed people in the DPR, something not  I
как-то взяли и убили в дн людей чтото не
can understand with you
могу понять с т вой
or about the fact that there are Nazis for someone. I did
или про то что там нацисты кого-то Я
n’t understand something. I just said
что-то не понял Это я сейчас сказал то
what now for 8 years or
что сейчас на протяжении 8 лет или
how long the Nazis have been terrorizing the DPR and
сколько там нацисты кошмарили ДНР и
LPR, it’s the Nazis. Well, who and how,
лнр именно нацисты Ну а кто а как вот
let’s do this  there is some Nazi how
давайте так вот есть какой-то нацист как
he specifically gave nightmares to the DPR LPR so that I
он конкретно кошмарил ДНР лнр чтобы я
could understand the process How this
понял процесс Как проходил этот
Nightmare went Well there they shot there they bombed the
Кошмар Ну там стреляли там бомбили там
girls there Dava Well the girls could have been in this
девушек Дава Ну в таком могли девушек в
if they couldn’t get there
том если они туда не могли попасть
because it was occupied by
потому что она оккупирована
Russia at that time it was Not  Well, for
Россией на то время было Не ну вот
example, in Donetsk, how in Donetsk there could be
например в Донецк как в Донецке могли
some I, now I’m not
какие-то я я сейчас не не не не Ниш
talking about the situation, but it was before
ситуации говорю а ещё было до того как
Russia attacked Ukraine, so to speak,
Россия так сказать напала на Украину вот
look, uh For example, six months ago,
смотрите ээ Вот например полгода назад
let’s take it like this, that is, there was this
возьмём так то есть была вот эта линия
demarcation line  no Nazi
разграничения никакие там нацисты
nationalists there could get into Donetsk,
националисты не могли попасть в Донецк
they weren’t there. That is, there
там их не было То есть там российские
were Russian troops there and these Russian
войска стояли и российские эти
militants were in Kharkov, look, Kharkov
боевики вот в Харькове смотрите Харьков
was there, there were Nazis there in Kharkov.
был были там в Харькове
I can’t find out. That is, it
нацисты Я не могу это узнать То есть
turns out these Nazis where they were, that
получается эти нацисты где они были то
is, They  people or something in Kharkov, it
есть Они людей что ли в Харькове
turns out there in
получается там в
Mariupol Well, that’s what I know, I just
Мариуполе Ну вот то что мне известно я
told you everything. And where do you get
вам сейчас всё сказал А откуда вот у вас
such sources of information so that I understand
такие источники информации чтобы я понял
How do you know this, well, the
Откуда вот вам такое известно ну
first is that I talked to a person
Первое это что я общался с человеком
here, he told me the
здесь он мне рассказывал
second Well  like telegrams of all sorts
второе Ну как телеграмы всякие
exist Well, you read there and well, you read and
существует Ну читаешь там и ну читаешь и
so on and so on yourself Well, you know, no matter what,
тому подобное и сам Ну понимаешь не коне
there are fake ones, there are fake ones, I won’t say anything,
есть фейковые есть фейковые я ничего не
yes,
да Да
nothing, yes, at home, many many don’t
ничего Да дома многие многие не
support many don’t support
поддерживают многие не поддерживают
the war, you hear me Yes, ho, against all this
войну вы слышите меня Да хо против этого
Well, just  here is the majority of people I
всего Ну просто вот большинство с кем я
communicate with from Russia. They are for the war for some reason,
общаюсь из России Они за войну почему-то
no. Even the most paradox is that
нет вот даже самый парадокс в том что
some kind of Progressive youth,
какие-то какая-то Прогрессивная молодёжь
maybe
может быть люди
show business people, maybe some kind of
шоу-бизнеса может Элита какая-то
political elite, everyone, let me and your
политическая все давайте я с вашим
colleague Yes, I’ll
коллегой Да
agree  with some one person and
договорюсь с каким-то одним человеком и
he told you something, the
он вам что-то рассказал
conclusion is
вывод
half
полу
well, because it’s clear from him that he won’t eat
ну да потому что по нему видно что он не
anything, look, it turns out if
что есть смотрите получается если вот
you now come across a person in chat roulette
вам сейчас в чат рулетке попадётся
who will say that he is
человек который будет говорить Что он
Putin’s nephew there and he eats
там племянник Путина и он съедает
for example, they
например пори
believed something Well, it’s just obvious from the person
верили что-то Ну там просто по человеку
that he’s there for me, even well, all sorts of things
видно то что он мне там даже ну всякие
there, no, look, you’re not talking about a Person,
там нене смотрите вы вы не про Человека
you’re saying that the Nazis are there in
говорите вы говорите что нацисты там в
Donetsk somewhere there are people who
Донецке где-то там людей это вам кто
told you this This person No, I’m just  it’s
сказал Этот человек Нет мне просто
known I read this here where they read it in
известно Я читал это вот где читали в
Telegram channels yes yes
Telegram каналах да да
anonymous Well I’ll even try to find it right now
анонимных Ну я даже сечас попробую найти
Well yes I’m just curious What sources of
Ну да Интересно просто Какие источники
information do you have for your picture of the world
информации у вас для картины мира вашей
I know about Sakhi you know how the story
мне про Сахи знаешь калько историю
was told to us by one Agent it turns out
рассказал нас же один Агент оказывается
Sakhi Well there’s a public here  I have a war in
Сахи Ну вот тут паблик есть у меня война
Ukraine right here now, that is, anonymous
Украина вот тут сейчас то есть анонимные
channels, so it turns out, yes. Well, I wouldn’t
каналы так получается да Ну как я не
say a million subscribers. Well, who
сказал бы миллион подписчиков Ну а кто
runs them? Who is
их ведёт Кто
the author? anonymous Well, yes, anonymously, I think
автор анонимно Ну да анонимно считаю да
yes, that is, it turns out, look,
да Вот то есть получается смотрите
a million, a million people read unknown
миллион миллион людей читает неизвестно
someone, that is, there  not so Here I am, for example,
кого то есть там не так Вот я например
if I express my thoughts, I say, here I am
если свои мысли излагаю я говорю вот я
Andrey and so on Further Yes And here it turns out it’s
Андрей и так Дальше Да А тут получается
unknown Who runs an unknown
неизвестно Кто ведёт неизвестно какой
Telegram channel due to the fact that there are a million
Telegram канал из-за того что миллион
subscribers, we believe him well, but
подписчиков мы ему верим хорошо а вот
look, now let’s say that they
смотрите вот сейчас допустим что в
were there in Ukraine  some Nazis,
Украине там были какие-то нацисты
how many people are they, for example, in the
сколько они вот людей например за
last year, according to your estimates?
прошлый год вот по вашим так прикидкам
Well, I don’t know. Well, I can’t say, I
Ну я не знаю Ну я не могу сказать же я
say, I read it, it wasn’t
говорю я вычитал это я там не было
written there how many people, but it’s not his
написано сколько людей но это же не он
year,
год же
don’t look, it just turns out  what now
Не смотрите просто получается что сейчас
I see it seems like they are telling us that the
я смотрю вроде нам говорят что 8 лет там
Nazis bombed Donbass there for 8 years, but Donetsk is
нацисты бомбили Донбасс но Донецк стоит
still standing fine No one bombed it, and
всё нормально Никто его не разбомбил а
Russian troops
Мариуполь российские войска за 2 месяца
wiped Mariupol off the face of the earth in 2 months, an aerial bomb, there are
стёрли с лица земли авиабомба всё там
no normal residential buildings there, so it
нет нормальных жилых зданий уже тобто
turns out that Russia came to
получается что Россия пришла
defend Donbass like that  and did destruction
защищать Донбасс так и сделал разрушение
and more than can be even
и больше чем вот вообще можно даже
imagined in that
представить на том
Donbass, what then is the logic
Донбассе в чём тогда логика
[music] of
[музыка]
defense? Well, seriously, it’s not that I
защиты Ну серьёзно я же не то что там
want to laugh or what happens.
хочу посмеяться или что вот получается
If I see, for example, a
Если я вот вижу например
guy a girl on the street, I come to
парень девушку на улице так я прихожу её
protect her  And at the same time, her mother is shorter. She is
защищать А при этом её маму короче Её
shorter than 10 people like and somewhere else a guy. Like it
короче 10 человек типа и гдето ещё парня
turns out
Типа так получается
like this. Well, even here I have now
так Ну даже вот я у меня сейчас была
such a story that when the plane was shot down
такая история то что когда самолёт сбили
there when it was flying past Ukraine Boeing
там когда он летел мимо Украины Боинг
Uh-huh Yes, he was shot down, who shot him down, the
Угу Да его же сбили кто его сбил
Russians  No, it’s already proven, too, the
россияне Нет это же Доказано уже тоже
whole world says that this is Russia Yes And you
весь мир говорит что это Россия Да А вы
say No, why am I not the only one who
говорите Нет ну почему я не я так один
says that, everyone says that it’s not Russia Well,
говорю все говорят то что не Россия Ну
who do I know who do I know I
кого я знаю кого я знаю в смысле в
mean, I’m not talking about Vasya Petya
смысле я говорю не про там Васю Петю
Kolya  there, such acquaintances there went out onto the
Колю там Вот таких знакомых там вышли на
street listening to Who shot down Bon, like they shot down
улицу слуша Кто сбил Бон типа сбили
for example, so, that is, there are
например так вот то есть есть
international institutions that
международные институции так которые вот
are conducting an investigation, that is, everything has been
проводят расследование то есть уже ж всё
known for a long time. Well, how do you know this,
известно Хорошо вам откуда Это известно
so look, not us, by the way, we
так смотрите Не мы у нас кстати мы
watched this  processes There was
наблюдали за этим процессами Вот был
probably such a tsemakh there, too,
такой наверно там цемах тоже
he gave evidence of which beech, so that
есть он давал показания какой бук так то
is, they established it there a long time ago with which
есть там установили уже давно каким
specific beech it was hit. Where to where they
конкретно буком сбита была Куда куда его
took him back to the territory of
вывозили потом назад на территорию
Russia and so
России и так
on Well, let’s say even we are behind now,
дальше Ну допустим даже мы сейчас отстав
I don’t want to unwind this  the topic with the
я не хочу вот разматывать эту тему с
plane is now going on The war Russia
самолётом вот сейчас идёт Война Россия
came under who was liberated near
пришла под ки кого освобождали под
Kiev
Киевом
in Borodyanka in the gostomel in all these
в бородянке в гостомеле вот во всех этих
cities they razed them to the ground
городах там что же сравняли с землёй их
That is, you want to say that Russia
То есть вы хотите сказать то что Россия
simply attacked Ukraine then that It
просто напала на Украину то чтом Скучно
was not boring Probably  they have some kind of
было нет Наверно у них есть какой-то
plan not to capture something, maybe they wanted to I
план что-то не захватить может хотели Я
don’t know Well, why seize Ukraine
не знаю Ну Для чего захватывать Украину
Well, someone in the Kremlin wanted to
Ну вот там кому-то в Кремле захотелось
restore the Empire No, it’s just I
это восстановить Империю Да нет просто Я
explained to you what I said that
же вам объяснил то что сказал что
Ukraine wants to join NATO to us
Украина хоте вступить в НАТО нам не
it wasn’t profitable, it’s good, look,
выгодно было это вот хоро смотри у
Ukraine will still join NATO.
Украина всё равно будет вступать в НАТО
So, that’s what has changed during these 3
Так ну вот что изменилось за вот эти 3
months of war. Well, look, if Ukraine
месяца войны Ну смотрите если Украина бы
Ukraine would join NATO, and
Украина вступила бы в НАТО бы и там
maybe there would be American military
может быть американские бы там военные
bases there, and we  they attacked Ukraine
базы стояли бы а мы напали на Украину
so that it wouldn’t join NATO, there’s no way she
чтобы она не вступила в НАТО она никак
could cede to NATO while the war is going on.
не смогла уступить НАТО пока идёт Война
Well, look no, why will they take it and
так Ну смотри не А почему возьмут и
join? Look at the weapons, how many weapons
вступят Вот смотри оружие сколько оружия
Ukraine had before the war, and now the
у Украины было до войны а теперь нам
whole world is giving us weapons, it turns out that
весь мир даёт оружие получается что у
we have Now
нас Теперь стало оружие больше чем чем
We are all given more weapons than we had before the war. Well,
было до войне нам все дают оружие Ну
of course, you all are
понятное дело вас всех ну вас
supported by the whole world. Why
поддерживают же весь мир А почему Россию
doesn’t the whole world support Russia? Well, that’s why it is
не поддерживает весь мир Ну вот почему
believed that Russia is supposedly
так считается то что якобы Россия - это
the aggressor. Well, why does everyone think
агрессор Ну во А почему все вот считают
that Russia  the aggressor, besides Syria,
что Россия агрессор кроме там Сирии
Belarus, there are two more countries there, well,
Белоруссии ещё двух стран там ну потому
because, well, the whole world
что ну весь мир
listens to the American media. That is, it
слушает американские СМИ То есть
turns out that the whole world has absolutely no
получается что весь мир так абсолютно не
opinion of its own, and everyone is dancing to
имеет свою мнение а все танцуют под
the tune of America, so of course, of course, that’s what
дудку Америки так получа конечно конечно
Ukraine wanted to do, too. But
как хотело сделать это и Украина А вот
look well  Come on, this is how you live.
смотри хорошо Давай так ты вот живёшь
Why say it like this, why does the world want to
Зачем скажем так зачем мир хочет
capture Russia then? Why do the Americans
захватить тогда Россию Зачем американцы
want to capture Russia there? Well, they won’t
хотят там захватить Россию ну они не
capture it; they won’t do it; but what kind of
захватят они не сделают а вот какую же
threat did we pose to Russia?
тогда угрозу мы представляли России Если
they
например натовские базы Так и что они
will want to take over Russia to
захотят захватить Россию
manipulate us like Well, tell us to
манипулировать нами как Ну скаже нам
do this what, well, we will have to
сделать это что ну надо надо будет
do it and
сделать а а
why why would you do it Americans
зачем зачем вы сделаете американцы
Americans want to show that they are
американцы хотят показать то что они
cool to the whole world So what But you wo
крутые на весь мир Ну и что А вот вы не
n’t do it And that the Americans will attack
будете делать И что американцы нападут
you  or what And why not oh that means
на вас или что А почему нет о то значит
that is, after all, the Americans want, in
вот то есть всё-таки американцы хотят по
your opinion, to attack Russia and
вашему мнению напасть на Россию и
seize it Yes, of course, Why should the
захватить её Да конечно во А зачем
Americans seize
американцам захватить
Russia because
Россию потому что конкуренты
competitors are competitors in what? Well, in terms of the fact that we have
конкуренты в чём Ну в плане то что у нас
such a big powerful country  and the
такая большая страна могущественная и
Americans, too, well, such a strong
американцы тоже ну такая такая сильная
power, they are also a world
держава тоже они же мирово
bridge, look, I would be there America and
мост смотрите вот я бы там Америка и
China are the two leaders in terms of GDP, so in terms of economy,
Китай два лидера по ВВП так по экономике
Russia has seven or eight times
Россия имеет там раз в Семь или восемь
less GDP there, so let’s say Let’s So
меньше ВВП так и допустим Давайте Так
what is Russia rich
чем богата Россия
in terms of in terms of  how rich Well, this is the
в плане в плане каком богатом Ну вот в
wealth of Russia, that they should
чём богатство России что на неё должны
attack it and take away this wealth. What is the
напасть и забрать это богатство В чём
gas?
газ О Газ Нефть там золото алмазы и так
Now let’s say in America
смотрите сейчас же допустим в Америке
the prices for gasoline have risen and the
поднялись цены на бензин и тому
like. They lived, they lived, well, before
подобное Они же жили они жили всё ну до
this, before this, before this, they lived
этого до этого они до этого они жили
happily ever after, everything was fine, they had it
получается припеваючи всё хорошо у них
there, don’t look, I mean, here’s
там было се не смотри я имею в виду Вот
the money from Russian gas, oil, who cares?  they
деньги из российского газа нефти кому
go to you to the Americans to Putin to
уходят тебе американцам Путину
whom I can’t tell, that is, it turns out that the
кому не могу сказать то есть получается
money of your country’s resources
деньги твои ресурсов твоей страны
is sold to the whole world and you don’t know who
продают всему миру и ты не знаешь кому
this money goes to, that’s how it
идут эти деньги так
turns out Well, who I don’t know, I
получается Ну кого я не знаю я так
don’t go that deep into politics,
сильно в политике не
this money from this goes to
углубляются эти деньги от этого идут
you no no oh  that is, look, the money from
тебе нет нет о то есть смотри деньги от
the resources of your country does not go to
ресурсов твоей страны не идут
you,
тебе в мда
there is someone who takes the resources of the seller, he
сть кто-то забирает ресурсы продат
receives money for himself on your behalf, he
получает себе деньги от твоего имени
also fights, but you have nothing from it
воюет также но тебе ничего с этого нет
if, for example, let’s do this if the
если например Давай так если захватили
Americans captured you, nothing would
американцы тебе так само ничего бы не
go well for you, it turns out that  has changed for you For
шло получается чтоб для тебя изменилось
example, if America had captured
Например если бы Америка захватила
Russia, I’m sorry, I’ll interrupt, you’re
Россию извини Вот перебью ты сейчас
talking about
говоришь про
corruption now. To the top, Well, we
коррупцию Т верхушкам Ну нам-то ничего с
don’t get anything from this. Well, look why. For example,
этого не Ну смотри почему Например
let’s take the Czech Republic without oil and gas, lives
возьмём Чехия без нефти и газа живёт
better than people in Russia live there. Well,
лучше чем люди в России там живут Ну
the state takes better care of  yes, that is, it
государство лучше заботится о да то есть
turns out, for example, the
получается э например в Страны НАТО
Czech Republic Poland is included in the NATO countries There and so on
входят там Чехия Польша Там и так дальше
Latvia Lithuania Estonia people live better
Латвия Литва Эстония люди живут лучше
than in Russia and another question is Ukraine
чем в России а ещё вопрос а Украина в
wants to join NATO in order to
НАТО хочет вступить для того чтобы
improve How is the quality of life or NATO
улучшить Как как качество жизни или НАТО
is not an economic Union  this is
- это не экономический Союз это
defensive, that is, Ukraine
оборонительный то есть в НАТО Украина
wants to join NATO because it considers Russia
хочет вступить потому что считает Россию
its threat so that Russia does
своей угрозой для того чтобы Россия на
not attack us, but why is
нас не нападала так а а по ну с какого
Russia considered a threat to
Россия считается Ну угрозой для для
Ukraine, they still say that these are the fraternal
Украины все же говорят что это братские
peoples of Ukraine, not I will say, I will say
народы украи не я скажу я скажу потому
because Russia has repeatedly attacked
что Россия неоднократно нападала на
Ukraine, and on and now on its neighbor it
Украину так и на и сейчас на соседе на
attacked Georgia, it also attacked, and in
Грузию нападала так тоже нападал и в
Russia there are a lot of politicians, and Zhirinovsky,
России куча есть и и Жириновский куча
yes, we need to annex Ukraine to
политиков да надо присоединить Украину к
Russia, maybe they talked about this
России может быть они это говорили с
with a kind ambassador. How kind we are not
добрым послом С каким добрым вот мы не
we want, that is, they are forcibly annexing us,
хотим то есть насильно нас присоединяют
well, this is already wrong, they will be forcibly
ну это это уже неправильно насильно
annexing, that is, look, if we are an
присоединят то есть смотри если мы
independent state. We want to be
независимое государство Мы хотим вот
friends with whoever we want, with the Americans, we want
дружить с кем хотим с американцами хотим
with the Poles, we want, if we want,
с поляками хотим если захотели с
we would be friends with the Russians, that is,
русскими дружили бы с русскими то есть
this is our right. That is, why us  we need to
Это наше право То есть почему нас надо
bomb because in the
бомбить изза того что мы
end he took and sold himself to the Americans. The
итоге он взял и продался американцам
Americans gave him we will support you. We ate
Американ нали ему мы тебя поддержим ели
there Russia, so in the end there are
там Россия на что в итоге Там просто
some private American military companies just howling
какието частные военные компании
there; they supply weapons; they are
американские там оружие поставляют
friends with the Americans; this is a reason to attack
дружит с американцами это повод нападать
Ukraine. Well,
Украину Ну
look, it turns out Russia and America  these are,
смотри получается Россия и Америка это
so to speak, two competitors, you can
ну так сказать два конкурента можно
say I don’t want to call them
сказать не хочу назвать их
enemies, how many sanctions have the Americans
врагами сколько там американцы санкций
imposed on us and the like, and so it
на нас накладывала и тому подобное и вот
seems to me that Russia is therefore not interested in
Ну мне кажется России поэтому не выгодно
you You have a store I have a
вы У тебя есть магазин У меня есть
store and some supplier
магазин так и какой-то поставщик
is starting to become friends  with this store you
начинает дружить с этим магазином ты
start setting fire to his warehouse like this
начинаешь поджигать ему склад так Потому
Because you don’t like that he is friends with your
что тебе не нравится что он с твоим
competitor Well, no, well, if
конкурентом дружит Ну нет ну если
such a situation really happens No, of course I wo
реально такая ситуация будет Нет конечно
n’t burn it down, but here the same thing
выжигать не буду во а а тут тоже самое
happens, why don’t we have the right to be
получается почему мы не имеем права
friends with those with whom  we want with a competitor
дружить с тем с кем хочем с конкурентом
not with a competitor Well, this is not a reason to
не с конкурентом Ну это же не повод
attack us, you yourself understand
нападать на нас сами близко понимаете
closely and that,
близко и что
but it seems to me that the Americans don’t communicate with anyone like that
а мне кажется американцы так ни с кем не
Well, it’s just as good as with
общаются Ну так прям хорошо как с
Ukraine and that Well, for example, well, the
Украиной и что Ну вот например ну любят
Americans love us And we are Americans and  so they
нас американцы А мы Американцы и так они
love you because of what, because of what, that you are
из-за чего вас любят из-за чего что вы
close to Russia, they want you to join
близко с россие хотят чтобы вступили в
NATO And that Well, look, they love us
НАТО И что Ну вот смотри любят они нас
there. We are in NATO there and why do
там включили Мы в НАТО там и что почему
we need to be bombed, attack us and
нас надо бомбить нападать на нас и
capture my point?  view that
захватывать сказа мою точку зрения что
most likely America can be used as
скорее всего Америка пользоваться может
your country and put its
быть вашей страной и поставить там свои
American bases there in order to
базы американские чтобы нами
manipulate us. Now, by the way,
манипулировать Вот теперь Кстати да вот
after this war, so after the start of it,
после этой войны так после начала его
Finland and Sweden Yes, they are applying to
Финляндия и Швеция Да подают заявки на
join NATO, this is also closer to you.
вступление в НАТО это ж от вас тоже
Look where  from St. Petersburg Ukraine And
ближе Вот смотри где от Питера Украина А
where is Latvia Lithuania Estonia nearby they are already in
где Латвия Литва Эстония рядом они уже в
NATO and Sweden Finland Soon they will also be
НАТО и Швеция Финляндия Скоро тоже будут
in NATO and Moldova also Moldova something
в НАТО и Молдова ещё Молдова что-что
Moldova is still far away yes,
Молдова ещ Молдова далеко далеко да то
that is, it turns out that you will attack
есть получается вы что будете нападать
Sweden on Finland Well, that’s not me anymore
на швецию на Финляндию Ну это я уже не
I can just say now, well, I’m judging what we
могу сказать я просто сейчас ну сужу что
have at the moment. Uh-huh. That is, it just
есть на данный момент Угу То есть просто
turns out that there are a lot of
получается что как бы возле России много
different countries near Russia that are either already in NATO or
разных стран которые или уже в НАТО или
going to NATO and attacked Ukraine. That is,
идут в НАТО а напали на Украину То есть
I don’t understand the logic then. Well, I don’t think
мне непонятна тогда логика Ну я не думаю
that  someone wanted it like this
то что это вот так вот захотелось
and he said something like go to Ukraine
кому-то и он сказал типа подм на Украину
No, it seems to me Well, this is some kind of nonsense It
Нет мне кажется Ну это бред какой-то Не
can’t be like that Well why Look, you
может быть такого Ну почему Смотри ты ты
said you’re not interested in politics,
говорил ты не интересуешься политикой
where is the money anyway, but it can’t be here anymore,
куда там деньги всё но тут уже не может
why?  it can’t be, or maybe the
быть а почему не может быть а может там
ruler there is just an old grandfather, you see for
правитель просто старый дедушка видите
yourself that who needs a war, neither you nor
сами то что кому нужна война нени Вам ни
us. But for the person who sits in the Kremlin,
нам Ну а человеку который сидит в Кремле
for example, maybe he wants to
например Может ему хочется там в историю
go down in history, maybe that’s what he himself
войти может быть такое он же сам
understands, that he is jeopardizing
понимает то что он ставит под угрозу
his  the people of their country, why does he need
свой народ свою свою страну зачем ему
this, well, look, this happened more than
это ну это вот смотри было такое у не
once that people in their old age, rulers
раз что люди на старости правители уже
were already out of their minds And they wanted to
исходили из ума И вот хотели там войти
go down in history to capture something. Well,
войти в историю что-то захватить Ну
look, if we are now talking
смотрите если мы сейчас говорим именно
about Putin, yes, he has already entered  in history as
про Путина Да он уже вошёл в историю как
Russia, at
России как
least as Yes, well, he is for now. I think he
минимум как Да ну он пока Мне кажется он
raised Russia, he did a lot. And
Россию поднял он много что сделал А
now
сейчас самая сильная армия это у
Russia doesn’t have the strongest army. What’s wrong? Of course it’s not
России не А что не так что ли Конечно не
so, well, American, uh, Well, yes, the American
так ну Американ ээ Ну да Американская
army is the strongest, look here  What
армия самая сильная смотрите вот вот у
we have now is that here
нас сейчас с вами получается то что вот
again, well, look at this Weapons These are
опять то что ну это смотрите Оружие Вот
the weapons that the Americans supply us with,
оружие которое поставляют нам американцы
so they are technologically better than the
так оно технологически лучше чем Вот то
junk that Russia is fighting with. Well, this is
старьё которым воюет Россия Ну это
objective. Do you know what they are fighting against Russia
объективно А вы знаете чем воют Россию
and what Soviet rubbish? Well, so be it
да чем советским хламом Ну ну так и есть
yes Well, we have reports of this
Ну так у нас есть отчёты вот этой
burnt equipment, if Russia, look,
спалено техники если Россия смотрите
such a powerful, most powerful army, why was
такая мощная самая мощная армия почему
it unable to capture Kiev? Why did
она не смогла захватить Киев Почему
it come up, get stars near Kiev and
подошла получила звездюлей под Киевом и
run away? Well, the question is Putin, in his entire
убежала ну вопрос Путин же в всё своё
administration, what did he do, just
управление он что делал только
arm it, and, well, launch it?  good
вооружать просто и ну запустить хорошее
equipment equipment and so on Further And where
оборудование технику и так Дале А где
where is this equipment Look, who doesn’t
где это оборудование Вот смотри воз не
want to
хочет всё
reveal everything, our heights
раскрывать высь наши
that is, not Look, you could
то есть не Смотри это можно было
laugh If it weren’t for a bunch of T That is, it
смеяться Если бы не было куча Т То есть
turns out look Putin throws
получается смотрите Путин кидает
Russian soldiers at old tanks without
российских солдат на старых танков без
active protection systems that  without bes, they
систем активной защиты та без бесп они
die, so ours are there with these
погибают так наши их там во с этих
British anti-tank and
британских противотанковых и
American ones, they shoot down the low And so on, and the
американских сбивают лоу И так дальше и
javelins and they die. That is, it
джавелины и они умирают То есть
turns out that they are not given modern
получается что им не дают современные
tanks, maybe they didn’t expect such
танки может быть не ожидал такого
resistance from Ukraine and this is so. And
сопротивления от Украины и этого так А
where is this then?  if you say that
где тогда вот это если вы говорите что
for the army for the army he armed himself with
на армию на армию он вооружился
modern tanks modern planes
современные танки современные самолёты
Perhaps you are expecting something that perhaps
Возможно вы ожидает чего-то что возможно
you are expecting
вы ожидает
something somehow Well, I say, it seems to me that
чего-то както Ну я говорю Мне кажется
this is not with all his might, he went so purely
это ну не во всю силу он пошёл так чисто
you know, here are the
знаете вот пе
pawn PTOs and so  exactly, even near
пешечные ВОМ так вот именно даже под
Kiev, how many thousands of your soldiers were
Киевом там сколько тысяч ваших ээ солдат
killed? Yeah, she died. That is, the
полегло Угу погибла То есть это что
pawn guys will come, well, who knows, we
пешечные приедут ребята ну кто знает мы
don’t know that, no one, neither you nor we
этого не знаем никто ни вы ни мы не
know, no, so we know with us, the war is going on,
знаем нет Так мы знаем у нас Война идёт
we’re running, we’re monitoring everything that’s happening
мы бегом мы мониторим всё что делается
now  both in Russia and in Ukraine, and in terms of the
сейчас и в России и в Украине так и по
balance of forces, yes, that is, we know,
соотношению сил да то есть мы мы знаем
we see howling at the World Cup, it just turns out,
мы видим на ЧМ воют просто получается
look, there is gas, there is oil, and so on the
смотрите есть газ там нефть и так дальше
money goes on. You don’t know where it’s going. So there are
деньги Вы не знаете куда идут Так танков
no new tanks, there are no new planes, where is
новых нет самолётов новых нет А куда же
the money then?  gone it
деньги тогда девались
turns out Well, of course, corruption
получается Ну понятное дело коррупция о
oh and who
а а кто их себе
took it for themselves the government the government yes,
забирал правительство правительство да
that is, it turns out that your
то есть выходит что ваше
government, say, takes the money for
правительство скажем забирает деньги
itself oligarchs from oil, gas and other
себе олигархи с нефти газа и других
natural resources,
природных ресурсов так
but it kind of explains to you that you need to
но как бы объясняет вам что вам надо
attack another country in order to
напасть на другую страну для того чтобы
some kind of America did not seize your
какой-то там Америка не захватила ваши
resources that do not belong to you,
ресурсы которые вам не принадлежат
it turns out Well, that is, I would understand if
получается Ну то есть я бы понимал если
there is so much gas from this oil. That is, you
там от этой нефти так газа То есть вы
would get something, but it turns out that
что-то бы получали но так получается
ordinary Russian citizens, Russians, they
простые русские граждане российские они
do not get anything from
ничего не получают от
this, this is a problem  already personal Well,
этого это проблема уже личного Ну
internal politics is a problem in
внутренняя политика это проблема же
many states, corruption is Well, I
многих государств коррупция то Ну имею в
mean, look, it turns out Czech Republic
виду что смотрите получается Чехия
Poland There and so on so they don’t have
Польша Там и так дальше так у них нет
such resources but they live better than
таких ресурсов но они живут лучше чем
people in Russia and Ukraine so but
люди в России и в Украине так но У
Russia has resources so in  In Ukraine,
России есть ресурсы так в Украине же
corruption is also thriving, corruption is
тоже процветает корупция коррупция вот
in all these post-Soviet countries Yes, but
на всех этих постсоветских странах Да но
we don’t have such a resource base of
у нас нет прям такой ресурсной базы
oil and gas, and so on and so on, that is, it
нефти газа и так дальше так то есть
turns out and we don’t attack anyone
получается и мы не нападаем ни на кого
tah mashbah they steal r speaking not on such a
тах машбах воруют г говоря не в таких
scale they steal they steal a lot yes  and
масштабах воруют воруют сильно да и у
we are struggling with this, and even here they are changing,
нас борятся с этим да и у нас меняют
for example, there the president can change
например там президентом могут поменяет
the Maidan in general, the Maidan, in short, what is the
Майдан в общем Майдан если коротко а что
Maidan? Well, Ask Let’s talk. Well, the
Майдана Ну Спросите Давайте поговорим Ну
overthrow about the Russian government
свержение про Российского правительства
and what not. Well, you say what you
и что не Ну вы говорите то что Вы
are trying to do so that in Russia
стараетесь сделать так чтобы в России
confirmation there is the
вот подтверждение там вот
Maidan What is the Maidan Tell me
Майдан Что что Майдан Вот скажите
Formulate the event itself the event itself
Сформулируй само событие само событие
How many people about 100 people
Сколько человек около 100 человек
died right at that time to
погибло же правильно в то время чтобы
overthrow the government wrong because of what
свернуть правительство не так из-за чего
they died that is, this Dictator
погибли то есть этот Диктатор
look at the people protesting without On the contrary,
смотрите людей митингующих безо Наоборот
I speak for Ukraine  support And
я за Украину говорю я в поддержку А
I understood something about the events in the Maidan just
понял я что-то события в Майдане как раз
against
вот против
the overthrow as about the Russian
свержения как про Российского
government of Poroshenko and the like of
правительства Порошенко и тому подобное
Yanukovych It seems like something like that I didn’t
Януковича Вроде бы да так что-то Не
understand again then you tell me
понял ещё раз то Вы расскажите про
something about the Maidan
Майдан что-то
And so Dear Sorry, I’m naked  with
А так Уважаемый Извините я с голым
my torso I’ll hide behind a friend, uh, well, I know
торсом Я за друга спрячусь э ну я знаю
that the event was Euromaidan Or how is it
что событие было Евромайдан Или как это
simply called Maidan, that’s right, I
просто Майдан называется правильно я
know a lot of victims were about 100
знаю много пострадавших было около 100
people died, that’s why, uh, it’s
человек погибло вот ну из-за чего Ээ это
like a rally, roughly speaking, it was very,
как митинг грубо говоря был такой очень
well, large-scale, so to curtail
ну крупномасштабный вот чтобы свернуть
Russia  about Russia, about the Russian
российско про российско про российское
government in Ukraine, I don’t
правительство в Украине я его не
show it. Correctly, I’m even talking here
показываю Правильно же говорю даже тут
not so much about the Russian one, that is,
даже не столько про российское то есть
it was so corrupt, so
оно было настолько коррупционное так вот
this Yanukovych, yes, that is, we have
этот Янукович да то есть у нас
oppressed
утесняемый
support, on the contrary,
поддержку наоборот вот скажите
please tell me, and you’re on tube. Don’t watch
пожалуйста а вы на тубе Не смотрите
Demetri Kartveli  evil Georgian Don’t
деметри картвели злого грузина Не
look no no well, but Khodorkovsky
смотрите нет нет ну а Ходорковского
Mikhail is who this one I I
Михаила это который этот которы я я пару
watched Navalny’s reports a couple of times about
раз отчёты Навального смотрел там про
Putin’s palace about this This is fake as
дворец Путина про это Это е фейк как
fake Well, that’s it And whose palace this is I don’t
фейк Ну вот так вот А чей это
know, maybe a person Well, not Putin for
дворец не знаю может человек Ну не Путин
sure, why  why do you believe so
точно а почему почему вот ты так веришь
Well, why should I believe Navalny
Ну а почему я должен верить навальному
not? Well, look, whose palace is
не Ну смотри а чей дворец
it?
этор Ну я не знаю может он чисто снял
come on,
например не Навального Хорошо давай так
Putin has palaces, well, he was one
у Путина есть дворцы ну он там был один
of them, most likely yes. Well, why can’t this
из скорее всего да Ну а почему этот не
be his palace? Well, how does
может быть его дворец посадил Ну откуда
the naval know that this is his palace, naval?
наваль знает что это его дворец наваль
Well, that is, who came, who
Ну то есть кто приезжал кто этож всё
established everything? He
устанавливает у него
doesn’t have that. That’s what I can  to say for sure that
нет Вот что я могу сказать точно то что
Navalny Stopudovo was poisoned by the same
Навального Стопудово отравил тот самый
person who now
человек котором сейчас общем которого
cannot be named in general Yes, I
нельзя называть Да я
understood this here, I agree even T
понял это это тут тут я согласен даже Т
argue
спори
100% Oh okay, yes guys, we’ve been talking for 30 minutes already,
100% О хорошо да ребята мы уже 30 минут
I understood the position, in short,
говорим я понял позицию короче
convince your friend so that he is
переубедить своего друга чтобы он был
against  wars, we don’t promote our
против войны мы не пропагандируя свои
views, we live as we do, but it’s
взгляды мы живём так как мы да но всё
still necessary somehow for a person who
равно надо надо как-то человеку каком
wants to help him figure it out, he’s
хочет пра помочь ему разобраться он
somewhere reading the wrong Telegram channels, he’s
где-то не те Telegram каналы читает
just reading Excuse you, what’s the name Andrey
просто Извините Вас как зовут Андрей
Andrey, you know, I’m to my friend
Андрей вот знаете я своему другу я к
I treat him well as my own
нему хорошо отношусь как к своему
person, I kind of let me explain, I’m
человеку я как бы давайте объясню я
Georgian and you understand what my
грузин и вы понимаете како какого я
opinion on this situation is, I explained to him
мнение по этой ситуации я ему объяснял
Well, he stands his ground anyway, I don’t know
Ну он стоит на своём всё равно я не знаю
how to explain to my friend, but he’s
как объяснить моему другу вот он всё
still on the same page  it’s worth it, you
равно вот на одном том же стоит
know, if he gets some
понимаете налете ему какого-то
good Georgian wine, maybe He’ll
грузинского вина хорошего может Он
understand Well, damn,
поймёт Ну бли
I don’t drink a way of life, yes, yes, I’m the
способ жизни я не пью да да я то же
same, the same with everything, guys,
самое то же самое с всё всё пацаны
Let’s Glory to Ukraine, I’ll run further Yes
Давайте Слава Украине побегу дальше Да
Sorry, please Sorry, please
Извините пожалуйста Извините пожалуйста
Can I ask you who you work for?  I'm a
Можно вопрос кем работаете из я по
programmer by first education, a
первому образованию программист по
lawyer by second, but I work as a programmer. And you talk so well. We thought, What if you're providing some kind of legal services, not me, legal services? I'm a lawyer by second education, but I'm not talking
образованию юрист но я разговариваю не
because I don't work as a lawyer. I
из-за того что юристом не работаю так Я
work as a programmer, it's just
работаю программистом это просто
education  It’s just that I’m an educated
образование Просто я образованный
person and that’s why I say I’m talking,
человек и поэтому говорю разговариваю
everything is fine,
всё хорошо
let’s sviya Oh so tsikavi yes there are
давайте свия О так таки цикави да бывают
characters htos there for vnu htos against
персонаж хтось там за вну хтось проти
such a bunch Ale dosit bachite lad
така компашка Але досить бачите хлопец
why so I read Telegram what
из-за чего так я читаю Telegram какой
Telegram channel is like that who knows it
Telegram канал такий то кто его веде
anonymous so in  him Million pisni VN
анонимный так в него же Мильон писни ВН
can’t Buti, that is, Lyudina rya istin
не може Бути по то есть Людина ря истин
Telegram channel for once in a long time
Telegram каналу по лько раз вго льон
mean the truth so Read mi live in
значить оце истина так Чите ми живе в
yakom information susp yakshto you will
якому информаций сусп якщо ти будеш
speak rozum river but in you there 10 PSV on
говори розум реч но в тебе там 10 ПСВ на
you will not be called  you can carry
тебе не будуть зважати а ти можеш нести
yakus dch in you lyon you nat nihto don’t
якусь дч в тебе льон ты нать нихто не
know who Nese yuch So well, tse Telegram
знае хто Несе юч Так ну це Telegram
channel z lyon write so VN vva na dumku
канал з льоном писни так ВН вва на думку
people people tse mean schos rose to that there
людей люди це значить щось розу тому там
lion lyu fields truth and threats and
льон лю поля правда и загрози да
we still need information Udo and  lion to that
информаций нам ще треба Удо и льва тому
piss Tes on th channel tse very-
пису Тесь на й канал це дуже-дуже
duzhe politely mi mamo ruhati correct thoughts and
важливо ми мамо рухати правиль думки и
bachite so that in us too buv lion piss and
бачите щоб в нас тоже був льон писки и
more people marvel at us Slava Steal pis
бильше людей нас дивись Слава Укра пись
on th Instagram I don’t know why is it
на й Instagram Я не знаю для чого це тоб
for why are you there to marvel at  office Ale
для чого тоб там дивитись на офес Але
for you tse about three clicks Ale you trimae
для тебе це о три клика Але ты тримае
me and I will be kasati Wow in me there Kupa
мене и я буду казати Вау в мене там Купа
folov and in me will be the best mood to
фолов и в мене буде класний настрий щоб
robiti nove cool video letter to my
робити нове крут видео пись на мий
Instagram Popik Andriy Oh
Instagram Попик Андрий О
so let me
так давай я теб
check for you and
чекаю а